HECTOR FELIX

m: (619) 400-7316 Hector.getEmail@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/hector-felix github.com/hector-felix



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven software engineer with a proven record of powering operational excellence using technology, data analysis and management paradigms to achieve maximum impacts with minimum resource expenditures for leading organizations. Detail-oriented professional with keen interpersonal, communication and organization skills, as well as software development, implementation, and design expertise. Demonstrated passion for Defense and Space Systems, contributing to the next wave of innovation with dedication and creativity.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Natural Curiosity and Eagerness to Learn
- Big-Picture Thinking
- Business Intelligence

- Design and Testing
- Versatile, Fast-paced
- Technophile

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Full Stack Development and Implementation

Savvy Problem-Solving Skills

Software Data Analysis

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, AUGUST 2020 (GPA: 3.5/4.0) | CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, DOMINGUEZ HILLS

Honors & Scholarships: Dean's List, Fall 2017 & Spring 2020; Stem Advantage Scholarship & Stem Scholar Achievement, Every Semester **Relevant Coursework:** Analysis of Algorithms, Software Engineering, Data Structures, Programming Languages, Operating Systems **Memberships:** Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers (SHPE), Member; Stem Scholars, Member; Stem Advantage, Member

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING/SCRIPTING LANGUAGES:

- Proficient in JavaScript, Python, Java, SQL
- Knowledgeable in C++, C, C#, HTML/CSS, .NET
- Familiar with GO, PHP, Ruby, Swift, TypeScript, GraphQL

TECHNOLOGIES: REST APIs, MERN Stack

- JavaScript ReactjS, Node.jS, Express.jS, Redux, jQuery
- **Python** Django, TensorFlow, PyTorch, NumPy, Keras, Pandas
- **Java** Hibernate, Spring, JDBC, Apache

TOOLS: Systems/Solutions Architecture, Systems Engineering, MongoDB, Express.jS, React.jS, Node.jS (MERN Stack), Java Web Development, Amazon Web Services(AWS), Heroku Cloud Services, GitHub, Docker/Kubernetes, BitBucket, Maven/Atlassian, Bootstrap, VMware, SLDC, Agile, UNIX, Linux Red Hat, OpenShift, Virtualization, Relational Database Systems, Object-Oriented Programming/Analysis, Microsoft Project Manager, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, Atom, MySQL, Xcode, ML applications, Neural Networks, Deep Learning, Git, JIRA, Jenkins

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OPERATIONS MANAGER | RUSH49 / TROLION APPS INC., EL SEGUNDO, CA, OCT. 2014 – PRESENT

- Engineer and launch a conversational Chatbot which draws upon a knowledge base and reliance factor to reply to users in real-time.
- Implement front- and back-end features and processes using applied business intelligence; redesign the customer account page that includes features such as email subscription preferences, payment profile, contact support option directly from the user account.
- Decreased fraud by 50% by identifying vulnerabilities and implementing fraud detection suite.
- Increased user traffic by 30% to website after designing a more user-friendly interface which discourages page abandonment.
- Make operational decisions and set strategic company goals in conjunction with senior executives.
- Oversee 15 staff members across departments, providing mentorship, development, and constructive feedback.
- Prepare for product deployment and optimize debugging process by testing features and web developments.

BRANCH MANAGER, SENIOR TAX ANALYST | H&R BLOCK, CORONADO, CA, OCT. 2013 - OCT. 2014

- Fostered a collaborative and results-driven office culture using positive recognition, team initiatives, and mentorship.
- Motivated employees to ensure productivity and timely completion of projects according to client needs.
- Consulted with clients to create a comprehensive tax plan for all situations and economic status.

RELEVANT PROJECT WORK & OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

SERVERLESS PORTFOLIO APPLICATION (AWS REST API) | LIVE APPLICATION

- AWS Resources: Lambda Functions, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Amazon S3; SAM CLI, AWS CLI, Node.jS
- Postman to aid in the API building process and automate testing of different HTTP methods against my API (GET, POST, PUT, DELETE)

CHATBOT, HOUSTON SPACE CENTER (PYTHON) | GITHUB | DEMO | FRAMEWORKS: TENSORFLOW, NATURAL LANGUAGE TOOLKIT, NUMPY

Leveraged machine learning, deep learning & neural networks to relay responses based on a confidence factor.

DARKLANG (NODE.jS), OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTION | GITHUB | SERVERLESS BACKENDS | HTTPS://DARKLANG.COM/, 2019 - PRESENT

Integration / Acceptance / Back-end / Tracing / Unit testing

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION - LANGUAGES: SPANISH; INTERESTS: TRAVELING, HIKING, SPACE EXPLORATION, FANTASY FOOTBALL, CHELSEA FC, BASKETBALL